ANAND CHOWDHARY

+31 644691056 +1 9092749233 +91 9555297989

mail@anandchowdhary.com @anandchowdhary anandchowdhary.com

SUMMARY

Full-stack JavaScript/TypeScript developer, designer, and entrepreneur based in the Netherlands with a focus on semantics

5+ years of part-time experience, and 3 years building my own web accessibility startup that scaled from 0 to 20,000+ monthly users, and a remote team of 10

10,000+ contributions to open-source projects in the past year, including #1 product on Product Hunt

Recipient of **30+ awards** and honors including Forbes 30 Under 30, Dutch Financial Times 50 Under 35, and TNW T500, and interviewed on TV and in 30+ publications and podcasts

Spoken at 20+ events about technology and startups around the world, including San Francisco, London, Paris, New Delhi, Amsterdam, and Kuala Lumpur

EXPERIENCE

Oswald Labs

Co-founder and CEO, 2016–2020 Built a web accessibility SaaS platform and consumer apps for people with disabilities

El Niño

Frontend Engineer, 2017–2019 Developed several React, Vue, and Angular.js apps for large-scale clients in the Netherlands and the UK

Government of Delhi

User Experience Design Intern, 2016 Material Design app prototype and UX research for Department of Education

Justice Adda

Technology Lead, 2015–2016 Website and apps for human rights and legal firm part of University of Cambridge

Freelance projects for several ecommerce and technology startups, 2014–2016

EDUCATION

University of Twente Creative Technology BSc 2017–2020, the Netherlands

Coursework includes CS and AI, smart tech, data visualization, UX research Honors program in Science

Santa Clara University

Global Engineering Education Exchange Fall 2019, California, United States

Minor coursework includes computer graphics, marketing, typography, VC Twente Mobility Scholarship